Guide to the David Burge Papers MSS.395
Fales Library and Special Collections
David Burge Papers
1947-2011
Fales Library and Special Collections
Burge, David, 1930-2013
MSS.395
19 Linear Feet
Burge was born in Evanston, Illinois and studied at the Eastman School of Music and the Cherubini Conservatory, Florence as a Fulbright scholar. He served on the faculty at the University of Colorado in Boulder during the 1960s and 1970s, founded and directed the Colorado Festival of Contemporary Music, and was Musical Director and Conductor of the Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra. Later, Burge chaired the Piano Department at the Eastman School of Music. Over his career, he gave more than 1,000 concerts in the United States, Europe, Asia, Australia and New Zealand, composed more than 100 works, authored the book Twentieth-Century Piano Music (Shirmer Books, 1990), wrote prize-winning columns for Keyboard Magazine, Clavier and The Piano Quarterly, and published the novel Vanishing Spring (1999). The David Burge Papers contain sheet music, scores, scripts, scrapbooks, photographs, media, and objects which document David Burge's personal and professional life.
Separated Materials
Books written by David Burge have been removed for cataloging.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note
David Burge was a pianist and composer. Born in Evanston, Illinois, in 1930, he earned bachelor's and master's degrees in music from Northwestern University, and a Doctor of Musical Arts degree and an artist's diploma from the Eastman School of Music in 1956.
While on the faculty at the University of Colorado in Boulder during the 1960s and 1970s, Burge founded and directed the Colorado Festival of Contemporary Music, and was Musical Director and Conductor of the Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra. During that period, George Crumb collaborated with Burge while writing Makrokosmos, a series of four volumes of pieces for piano. Burge also worked with composers such as Ernst Krenek, Luciano Berio, and Karlheinz Stockhausen, and singers including Cathy Berberian and Bethany Beardslee.
After leaving the University of Colorado, he chaired the Piano Department at the Eastman School of Music for many years. Over his career, he gave more than 1,000 concerts in the United States, Europe, Asia, Australia and New Zealand, composed more than 100 works, authored the book Twentieth-Century Piano Music (Shirmer Books, 1990), wrote prize-winning columns for Keyboard Magazine, Clavier and The Piano Quarterly, and published the novel Vanishing Spring (1999). He won Ascap-Deems Taylor Awards in 1978 and 1979 for his writings in Contemporary Keyboard magazine.
For about a decade starting in the mid-1990s, he was composer in residence with the San Diego Ballet. He accepted visiting professorships at universities and conservatories in the United States, Denmark, Turkey, New Zealand, Canada, Australia, Sweden, and Korea.
Burge died from a heart attack on April 1, 2013 in Warwick, Rhode Island.
Scope and Content
The David Burge Papers contain sheet music, scores, scripts, scrapbooks, photographs, media, and objects that document David Burge's personal life and his work as a pianist, composer, and writer.
Arrangement
The David Burge Papers are organized into eight series:
Missing Title
Series I: Music by David Burge
Series II: Notebooks
Series III: Scores
Series IV: Books
Series V: Photographs
Series VI: Media
Series VII: Objects
Series VIII: Posters and Artworks
The collection has been kept in the original order in which it was recieved.
Provenance
The David Burge Papers were donated to NYU's Fales Library & Special Collections by Evon Burge in 2014.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Piano music.; Sheet music.; Music -- Manuscripts.; Musical theater -- United States; Silsbee, Ann; Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991; Boulez, Pierre, 1925-; Berio, Luciano, 1925-2003; Cage, John; Crumb, George; Wuorinen, Charles; Albright, William; Bartok, Bela, 1881-1945; Burge, David, 1930-2013
- Series I: Music by David Burge
  Scope and Content
  This series contains sheet music and writings by David Burge.
  - PIANO - First Sonata (1948); Katherine Suite (1952?); Sonatina (1958) [GREEN FILE], 1948-1958 (Box 1)
  - PIANO - Improvisations (1953); Six Piano Pieces (1958) [GREEN FILE], 1953-1958 (Box 1)
  - PIANO - Second Piano Sonata (1958) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - PIANO - Third Piano Sonata (1959); Fourth Piano Sonata (1962) [GREEN FILE], 1959-1962 (Box 1)
  - VIOLIN - Danses Fantastiques (1948); Sonata for Violin and Piano (1950?) [GREEN FILE], 1948-1950 (Box 1)
  - VIOLIN - Sonatina for violin and piano (1960) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - VIOLIN - Prelude (1948); Movement in G minor (1948); Sonata for violin and viola (1950?); Movement for Solo Violin (1951) [GREEN FILE], 1948-1951 (Box 1)
  - CHAMBER - Trio (1962); Quintet for Piano and Strings (1958) [GREEN FILE], 1958-1962 (Box 1)
  - CHAMBER - Flute Sonata (1955) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - CHAMBER - The Pink Elephant Suite (1947); First String Quartet (1950) [GREEN FILE], 1947-1950 (Box 1)
  - CHAMBER - Music for violin, voice, and piano (1952); Wind Quintet (1955) [GREEN FILE], 1952-1955 (Box 1)
  - ORCHESTRA - Piano Concerto (1956) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - ORCHESTRA - Concerto for Viola and Orchestra (1959) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - VOCAL - Agnus Dei (1949); Pie Jesu (1952); Lighten Our Darkness (1952); Vanishing Spring (1953); Portami il Girasole (1957) [GREEN FILE], 1949-1957 (Box 1)
  - VOCAL - Song (1952); My Love (1952); Choral Music written in Korea (1953-54) [GREEN FILE], 1952-1954 (Box 1)
  - VOCAL - Songs from "Popoff" (1961) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - THEATER - Popoff (1961) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - THEATER - Intervals (1961) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - THEATER - Blood Wedding (1951); Infernal Machine (1952) [GREEN FILE] (Box 1)
  - PIANO - Eclipse I (1963); Eclipse II (1966) [YELLOW FILE], 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - PIANO - Sources IV (1969) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - VIOLIN - Sources II (1965) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - CHAMBER - Sources I (1964) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - CHAMBER - Nun Danket alle Gott (1966) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - CHAMBER - String Quartet II (1969) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - ORCHESTRA - Serenade II (1965) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - VOCAL - A Song of Sixpence (1967); Songbook (undated) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - OTHER - Study for Two Conga Drums (1966) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - OTHER - The Ash Grove (1969) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - OTHER - Twone in Sunshine (1969) [YELLOW FILE] (Box 1)
  - KEYBOARD MAGAZINE - Greensleeves (1978); Good King Wenceslavs (1979) [ORANGE FILE], 1978-1979 (Box 1)
  - KEYBOARD MAGAZINE - Variations on Simple Gifts (1980); Lorca: Lament (1988) [ORANGE FILE], 1980-1988 (Box 1)
  - PIANO - Cadenza K. 491 (1989); Soft Shoe-Shoe Rag (1985); Zazita's Delight (1985) [RED FILE], 1985-1989 (Box 1)
  - PIANO - Go-Hyang (1994); Liana's Song (1995) [RED FILE], 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - PIANO - Three Tiny Piano Pieces (1995); 24 Preludes (1996) [RED FILE], 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - VIOLIN - Romance (1995) (Box 1)
  - VIOLIN - Sonata for Violin and Piano (1994, revised 1999) (Box 1)
  - VIOLIN - Two Short Pieces (1982) (Box 1)
  - CHAMBER - Moku (1998) [RED FILE] (Box 1)
  - ORCHESTRA - Dances of Love and Laughter (1998) [RED FILE] (Box 1)
  - VOCAL - Life Begins at 40 (1998) [RED FILE] (Box 1)
  - VOCAL - Songs of Love and Sorrow (1989) [RED FILE] (Box 2)
  - VOCAL - Gloria del Disteso Mezzogiorno (1985); Candytata (1994) [RED FILE], 1985-1994 (Box 2)
  - VOCAL - Yawn Shim (Loving Heart) (1995); Ehyeh Asher Ehyeh (1998) [RED FILE], 1995-1998 (Box 2)
  - VOCAL - Morning Song (1999) [RED FILE] (Box 2)
  - DANCE - Luna Lunera (1996) [RED FILE] (Box 2)
  - DANCE - The Dark Journey (1995) [RED FILE] (Box 2)
  - PIANO - Rainbows (2003) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - PIANO - Three Piano Pieces (2004) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - PIANO - Music of Love - For Evon (2011) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - VIOLIN - Azaleas (2005) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - VIOLIN - Reminiscence (2004); Huckleberry Lane (2004) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - CHAMBER - Emma's Day (2005) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - CHAMBER - Kaleidoscope (2001) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - OTHER - Kensington Capers (2001) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - OTHER - When Love Prevails (vibraphone) (2002) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - OTHER - Theme and Variations (guitar) (2002) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - VOCAL - La Noche del Huerto (2003) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - VOCAL - Five Folksongs (2006) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - VOCAL - La Noche del Huerto (2005) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - VOCAL - Marisa's Songbook (2005) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - VOCAL - Collected Songs (undated) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - DANCE - The Thousand Paper Cranes (2001) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - DANCE - Loteria (revised - 2002) [BLUE FILE] (Box 2)
  - MISC - Student Works, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
  - MISC - Plays, 2002; Undated (Box 2)
  - MISC - List of Works, Undated (Box 2)
- Series II: Notebooks
  This series contains notebooks and photo albums created by David Burge. It includes correspondence, flyers, photographs, and other memorabilia.
  - Burge letters home - Book I (1952-53), Army, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
  - Burge letters home - Book II (1953-54), Army (Korea), 1953-1954 (Box 3)
  - Burge letters home - Book III (1954-57), Rochester, Italy, 1954-1957 (Box 3)
  - Burge letters home - Book IV (1957-75), Walla Walla, Boulder, 1957-1975 (Box 3)
  - Burge in Academia / Family - Book I, Whitman (1957-62), University of Colorado (1962-75), 1957-1975 (Box 3)
  - Burge in Academia / Family - Book II, Eastman (1975-87), 1975-1987 (Box 3)
  - Burge in Academia / Family - Book III, Eastman (1987-93), 1987-1993 (Box 3)
  - Burge Performances, Tours, Recordings, Programs, Reviews, Repertoire - Index (1945-2010) (Box 3)
  - Burge Performances, Tours, Recordings, Programs, Reviews, Repertoire - Book I (1948-72), 1948-1972 (Box 3)
  - Burge Performances, Tours, Recordings, Programs, Reviews, Repertoire - Book II (1973-75), 1973-1975 (Box 4)
  - Burge Performances, Tours, Recordings, Programs, Reviews, Repertoire - Book III (1975-81), 1975-1981 (Box 4)
  - Burge Performances, Tours, Recordings, Programs, Reviews, Repertoire - Book IV (1981-93), 1981-1993 (Box 4)
  - Burge Performances, Tours, Recordings, Programs, Reviews, Repertoire - Book V (1993-99), 1993-1999 (Box 4)
  - Burge Performances, Tours, Recordings, Programs, Reviews, Repertoire - Book VI (1999-2010) (Box 4)
  - Burge in Publications - Book I, Keyboard Magazine (1975-84), 1975-1984 (Box 4)
  - Burge in Publications - Book II, Keyboard Magazine (1985-89), 1985-1989 (Box 4)
  - Burge in Publications - Various (1986-92), 1986-1992 (Box 4)
  - Burge in Publications - Various (1973-2002) (Box 4)
  - Burge in Publications - Various (1999-2010) (Box 4)
  - Burge Compositions, Programs, Reviews (1947-2006) (Box 5)
  - Burge Directs Boulder Philharmonic, Programs, Reviews (1965-72), 1965-1972 (Box 5)
  - Burge Directs Boulder Contemporary Festival, Programs, Reviews (1966-72), 1966-1972 (Box 5)
  - Burge Photo Albums - Book I (1930-52), 1930-1952 (Box 5)
  - Burge Photo Albums - Book II (1952-57), 1952-1957 (Box 5)
  - Unpublished Typescripts - Trip to Romania (1974) (Box 6)
  - Unpublished Typescripts - Trip to Far East (1984) (Box 6)
  - Unpublished Typescripts - Collection: Poetry, Witchcraft and Adventure (1990) (Box 6)
  - Unpublished Typescripts - Ballet: One Thousand Paper Cranes (2001) (Box 6)
  - Burge Friends - Book I, Undated (Box 7)
  - Burge Friends - Book II, Undated (Box 7)
  - Composers and Performers, Undated (Box 7)
  - Teachers, Colleagues, Classmates, Undated (Box 7)
  - Students - Book I, Undated (Box 7)
  - Students - Book II, Undated (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts - The Ghosts are Waiting (1984) (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts - Vanishing Spring (1994) (Box 7)
  - Manuscripts - Silence (2008) (Box 7)
  - Noyes School 6th Grade scrapbook, 1941 (Box 7)
- Series III: Scores
  This series contains scores written by and or performed by David Burge.
  - Burge Scores - Intervals, Undated (Box 8)
  - Burge Scores - Piano Concerto parts; Twone in Sunshine, Undated (Box 9)
  - Burge Scores - Popoff, Undated (Box 10)
  - Performance Scores - Albright, William: Pianoagogo, The Dream Rags, Five Chromatic Dances, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Barber, Samuel: Sonata for Piano, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Bartok, Bela: Deuxieme Sonate, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Beatles: Yesterday (Burge arrangement for Berberian performance), Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Berg, Alban: Sonate fur Klavier, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Berio, Luciano: Sequenza IV; Cinque Variazioni, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Boulez, Pierre: Premiere Sonate; Deuxieme Sonate, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Brusletten, Irvin: 9 Haiku for Piano, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Bussotti, Sylavano: Five Piano Pices for David Tudor, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Cage, John: Dream; Etude Australes, Undated (Box 11)
  - Performance Scores - Chaitkin, David: Etudes, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Chavez, Carlos: Sonatina, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Copland, Aaron: Piano Sonata, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Crumb, George: Five Pieces for Piano; Gnomic Variations; Makrokosmos I & II, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Curtis-Smith, C.: Rhapsodies, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Davidovsky, Mario: Synchronisms No. 6, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Eakin, Charles: Frames, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Falla, Manuel de: Fantasia Baetica, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Fisher, Alfred: At Winter's End; Six Fantasy Pieces, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Gershwin, George: Concerto in F, Undated (Box 12)
  - Performance Scores - Hamer, Jan: Two Morning Asanas for Piano, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Hanson, Howard: Fantasy Variations on a Theme of Youth, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Henkemans, Hans: Sonata, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Ince, Kamren: The Blue Journey, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Krenek, Ernst: Piano Sonata No. 4, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Martirano, Salvatore: Cocktail Music, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Myoshi, A.: Chaines, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Perschetti, Vincent: Ninth Piano Sonata, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Putz, Kevin: Minimalist Rag, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Riley, Dennis: Piano Piece No. 1, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Rochberg, George: Twelve Bagatelles, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Silsbee, Ann: Doors; In & Out the Window, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Stockhausen, Karlheinz: Klavierstuck VII & VIII, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Takemitsu, Toru: Les Yeux Clos, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Walker, George: Piano Sonata No. 2, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Weber, Ben: Fantasia, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Wilson, Richard: Eclogue, Undated (Box 13)
  - Performance Scores - Wuorinen, Charles: Piano Variations, Undated (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Albright, William: Three Novelty Rags; Introduction, Passacaglia, and Rondo Capriccioso; Grand Sonata in Rag; The Machine Age; Steptime for George's Birthday; A Ragtime Lullabye; New Leaves, Undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Bacewicz, Grazyna: Sonata, Undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Bartok, Bela: Selected Works for the Piano; Petite Suite; Out of Doors; Third Piano Concerto, Undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Berio, Luciano: Circles, Undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Boulez, Pierre: Structures, Undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Curtis-Smith, C.: Tristana Variations, Undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Durko, Zsolt: Psicogramma, Undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Enescu, Georges: Suita in Stil Vechi; Troisieme Sonate; Impressions d'Enfance; Variatiuni, Undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Fisher, Alfred: Two Tableaux from the Life of Isolde; Speak, Love; Last Dance; A Heart Untainted; Six Fantasy Pieces, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Griffes, Charles: Fantasy Pieces, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Halffter, Rudolfo: Sonata, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Honegger, Arthur: Sept Pieces Breves, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Ives, Charles: Three Page Sonata, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Kocsar, Miklos: Improvvisazioni, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Kodaly, Zoltan: 7 Pieces pour le Piano, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Krenek, Ernst: Piano Piece in Eleven Parts; Twenty Miniatures; Sonata No. 5; Sonata No. 6; Twelve Variations, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Martin, Frank: 8 Preludes pour le Piano, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Martino, Donald: Impromptu for Roger, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Moussorgsky, Modeste: Picture at an Exhibition, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Riley, Dennis: Five Little Movements, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Rochberg, George: Prelude on "Happy Birthday"; Sonata-Fantasia, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Scriabine, Alexander: Selected Compositions, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Serocki, Kazimierz: Piacere, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Silsbee, Ann: Journeys, Hymn, and Ceremonies, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Stockhausen, Karlheinz: Klavierstucke, I-IV, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Walker, George: Piano Sonata No. 1, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Wuorinen, Charles: Bagatelle, Undated (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Scores - Yun, Isang: 5 Stucke fur Klavier, Undated (Box 15)
- Series IV: Books
  This series contains books from David Burge's library. Books written by David Burge have been removed for cataloging.
  - "The Death of Anton Webern" - Hans Moldenhauer, 1961 (Box 17)
  - "The Death of Anton Webern" removed papers, Undated (Box 17)
  - "The Evanstonian of '47" - 45th, 50th, 55th reunions, 1996-2003 (Box 17)
  - "The Evanstonian of '47" - yearbook, 1947 (Box 17)
  - "Evanstoniana" - Barbara J. Buchbinder-Green, 1984 (Box 17)
  - Fort Eunice Transportation Center yearbook, 1952 (Box 17)
  - "Kunst og Kamp" - Gerd og Aksel Schiotz, 1951 (Box 17)
  - "La Vie du Pianiste Dinu Lipatti" - Anna Lipatti, 1954 (Box 17)
  - "Musikhost 99" - Festival for NY Musik program, 1999 (Box 17)
  - "Northwester University 93rd Annual Commencement" program, 1951 (Box 17)
  - Northwestern University Alumni Awards, 1974 (Box 17)
  - "A Pictorial History of Northwestern University", 1951 (Box 17)
  - "Recoutres avec Pierre Boulez" - Anoine Golea, 1958 (Box 17)
  - "The Score 1955" Eastman School yearbook (Box 17)
  - "The Score 1956" Eastman School yearbook (Box 17)
  - "A Soprano on Her Head" - Eloise Ristad, 1982 (Box 17)
  - "A Soprano on Her Head" - removed papers, Undated (Box 17)
  - "The Unashamed Accompanist" - Gerald Moore, 1946 (Box 17)
- Series V: Photographs
  This series contains photographs of David Burge, with family and friends.
  - Photographs of Burge, Undated (Box 2)
  - Framed photograph of Chang Kyong Ai, Undated (Box 16)
- Series VI: Media, Burge, David, 1930-2013
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  Crumb, George; Cage, John
  - Sound recordings- Originals
    - 20th Century Piano Music, 2003; ID: 395.0001; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0001)
      Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
    - The Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra, 1965; ID: 395.0002; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0002)
    - The Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra, 1967; ID: 395.0003; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0003)
    - The Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra, 1968; ID: 395.0004; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0004)
    - The Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra, 1968; ID: 395.0005; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0005)
    - The Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra, 1969- 1970; ID: 395.0006; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0006)
    - The Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra, 1971; ID: 395.0007; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0007)
    - The Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra, 1971; ID: 395.0008; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0008)
    - The Boulder Philharmonic Orchestra, 1971; ID: 395.0009; Orignal format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0009)
    - Dances and Songs by David Burge, 1999; ID: 395.0010; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0010)
    - Improvisations and Sonatas (1 of 2), 2010; ID: 395.0011; Original format: CD, wrapped in original plastic (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0011)
    - Improvisations and Sonatas (2 of 2), 2010; ID: 395.0012; Original format: CD, wrapped in original plastic (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0012)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. I - William Albright, undated; ID: 395.0013; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0013)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. II - George Crumb, undated; ID: 395.0014; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0014)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. III - Wuorinen, Silsbee, Curtis-Smith, Ward0Steinman, Lewis, Martirano, undated; ID: 395.0015; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0015)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. IV - Hamer, Crumb, Eakin, McLean, Hudson, Rochberg, undated; ID: 395.0016; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0016)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. V - Berg, Schoenberg, Webern, Kodaly, undated; ID: 395.0017; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0017)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. VI - Bartok, Stravinsky, Dallpiccola, Krenek, undated; ID: 395.0018; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0018)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. VII - Boulez, Stockhausen, Berio, undated; ID: 395.0019; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0019)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. VIII - Early Music - 1952-1962, Undated; ID: 395.0020; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0020)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. IX - Early Music - 1952-1962, undated; ID: 395.0021; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0021)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. X - Avant Garde period - 1962 - 1969, undated; ID: 395.0022; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0022)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XI - Avant Garde period - 1963 - 1969, undated; ID: 395.0023; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0023)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XII - Later Music - 1982-2004, undated; ID: 395.0024; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0024)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XIII - Later Music - 1982 - 2004, undated; ID: 395.0025; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0025)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XIV - Later Music - 1982 - 2004, undated; ID: 395.0026; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0026)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XV - Later Music - 1982 - 2004, Undated; ID: 395.0027; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0027)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XVI - Liana's Song, Sonata for Violin and Piano, Go-Hyang, Undated; ID: 395.0028; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0028)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XVII - Azaleas, 2005; ID: 395.0029; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0029)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XVIII - Improvisations and Sonatas, 2010; ID: 395.0030; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0030)
    - Music by David Burge, Vol. XIX - Songs of David Burge, 2009; ID: 395.0031; Original format: CD (Box 18, Media ID: 395.0031)